Mss.B.V462
American Philosophical Society
- Series I: Correspondence, 1768-1922; c. 850 items.
  - Letter to [E.W. Clark?], May 24, 1890; Wistar, Annis Lee
    Refers to Clark’s daughter’s marriage. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Marion [C. Madeira], Oct. 2, 1890; 4 1/2" x 6 3/4"; Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909
    A.L.S. 4p. Congratulations to her marriage. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Marion [C. Madeira], Oct. 12, 1890; 4 1/2" x 7"; Furness, William Henry, 1802-1896
    A.L.S. 1p. Congratulations to her marriage. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [E.W. ?] Clark, Nov. 9, 1891; 4 1/2" x 7"; Conway, Moncure Daniel, 1832-1907
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. Refers to Mr. Hinckley as a "warm hearted Theist much of the type of Longfellow." MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Joseph MacLean, Oct. 5, 1894; 8" x 5 1/4"; Pillsbury, Parker, 1809-1898
    Concord,N.H., A.L.S. 2p. and envelope. Refers to his request for a book. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Joseph MacLean, Oct. 8, 1894; 5 1/2" x 3 1/2"; Pillsbury, Parker, 1809-1898
    Concord, N.H., A.L.S. 1p. and add. Thanks for his patronage. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [Louis C. ?] Madeira, Dec. 5, 1900; 8" x 10 1/2"; Eberle, Edward Walter, 1864-1929
    Annapolis, T.L.S. 2p. Reagrading a football game. Thanks for courtesies during visit. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Edward [Clark], Nov. 6, 1902; 5 3/4" x 6 1/2"; Cooke, Jay, 1821-1905
    Ogontz, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Sending bottles of wine.
  - Letter to Mrs. Edw[ar]d W. Clark, April 9, 1904; 5 1/4" x 6 3/4"; Cooke, Jay, 1821-1905
    Ogontz, Pa., A.L.S. 3p. Letter of condolences; laments the loss of his very close friend Edward. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Mrs. Clark, April 19, 1904; 4 1/2" x 6 3/4"; Doane, William Croswell, 1832-1913
    Albany, A.L.S. 1p. Friendly letter. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Edith Madeira, April 15, 1910 (?); 6" x 7"; Repplier, Agnes, 1855-1950
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Birthday greetings. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, May 4, 1910; 6 1/2" x 8"; Harrison, Charles Custis, 1844-1929
    Philadelphia, T.L.S. 1p. Informs him of election to Board of Trustees Of Univ. of Pennsylvania. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, Oct. 21, 1910; 5 1/4" x 6 3/4"; Anshutz, Thomas Pollock, 1851-1912
    Fort Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Refers to frame for Mrs. Madeira. Details expenses. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, Nov. 4, 1910; 6" x 9 1/4"; Saving Fund Society of Germantown and its Vicinity
    Philadelphia, A.L.S: Elliston P. Morris, secretary. 1p. Informs him of election as manager. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Mrs. Madeira, June 1(?), 1911; 5 3/4" x 6 3/4"; Washington, Booker T., 1856-1915
    Tuskegee institute, Alabama, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks her for her donation. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to L.O.[i.e.C.] Madeira, Jan. 25, 1913; 8 1/2" x 11"; Hibben, John Grier, 1861-1933
    Princeton, T.L.S. 1p. Regarding Board of Trustees of Princeton. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, Jan. 25, 1913; 8" x 10 1/2"; Lowell, A. Lawrence (Abbott Lawrence), 1856-1943
    Cambridge, T.L.S. 1p. Regarding governing body of Harvard. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis O. [i.e. C.] Madeira, Jan. 25, 1913; 8 1/2" x 11"; Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1838-1913
    New Haven, Conn., T.L.S. 1p. Regarding governing body of Yale. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Edward W. Madeira, June 5, 1915; 7" x 9 1/4"; Lansing, Robert, 1864-1928
    Washington, T.L.S. 1p. Thanks for sending copy of U Penn Law Review. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, Oct. 13, 1915; 5 1/4" x 6 3/4"; Rockefeller, John D., (John Davison), 1874-1960
    New York, T.L.S. 1p. Thanks for compliments about road to Jordan Pond. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, Feb. 19, 1916; 8" x 10 1/2"; Beveridge, Albert Jeremiah, 1862-1927
    Beverly farms, Mass., T.L.S. 1p. Thganks for two Jefferson letters. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, Feb. 24, 1916; 6 3/4" x 9 1/4"; Rowe, L. S. (Leo Stanton), 1871-1946
    Philadelphia, T.L.S. 1p. Madeira as life member of the American Academy of Political and Social Science. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Made[i]ra, March 21, 1917; 8 1/2" x 11"; Brumbaugh, Martin Grove, 1862-1930
    Harrisburg, T.L.S. 1p. Appoints him to Committee of Public Safety. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Samuel Madeira, June 13, 1917; 8" x 10 1/2"; Beveridge, Albert Jeremiah, 1862-1927
    Boulderwood, Mass., T.L.S. 1p. Refers to his biography of John Marshall. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, Aug. 13, 1917; 5 3/4" x 6 3/4"; Morris, Roland S. (Roland Sletor), 1874-1945
    Philadelphia, T.L.S. 1p. Thanks for his wishes to appt. as Ambassador to Japan. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, July 28, 1917; 8 1/2" x 11"; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    [Washington] T.L.S. 1p. Regarding Food Control Bill. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, Nov. 13, 1917; 8 1/2" x 11"; Kuhn, Otto
    New York, T.L.S. 1p. Thanks for commendation. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, Dec. 13, 1917; 5" x 8"; Falconer, Robert, Sir, 1867-1943
    Toronto, T.L.S. 2p. Thanks for invitation to be his guest during visit to Philadelphia. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [ ] Madeira, March 21, 1918; 8 1/2" x 5 1/2"; Rhinelander, Philip Mercer, 1869-1939
    Philadelphia, T.L.S. 1p. Invitation to meet at his house with the Archbishop of York. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [ ] Madeira, Nov. 14, 1918; 4 1/4" x 6"; Rhinelander, Philip Mercer, 1869-1939
    Germantown, A.L.S. 2p. Condolences re. his brother's death. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [Louis C. ?] Madeira, Dec. 23, 1918; 6" x 4 1/2"; Falconer, Robert, Sir, 1867-1943
    University of Toronto, A.L.S. 1p. Christmas wishes. Witnessed a battle while in Europe. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis [C.] Madeira, July 7, 1919; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Richmond, Charles Alexander, 1862-1940
    Pointe-au-Pic, P.Q., Canada, T.L.S. 1p. Friendly letter. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, July 8, 1919; 5" x 8"; Rowe, L. S. (Leo Stanton), 1871-1946
    Washington, T.L.S. 1p. Regarding expedited action on his son's application for discharge.
  - Letter to G.W. Edmonds, July 21, 1919; 8" x 10 1/2"; March, Peyton Conway, 1864-1955
    Washington, T.L.S. 1p. Re. discharge of Crawford C. Madeira.
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, July 22, 1919; 8" x 10 1/2"; Edmonds, George Washington, 1864-
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, Jan. 27, 1920; 8" x 10"; Sims, William Sowden, 1858-1936
    Newport, R.I., T.L.S. 1p. Declines invitation to stay with him during Penn comencement.
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, May 25, 1920; 8 1/2" x 11"; Beveridge, Albert Jeremiah, 1862-1927
    Indianapolis, T.L.S. 1p. Thanks for invitation to stay with him during Penn commencement.
  - Letter to Louis C. Madeira, Jan. 31, 1922; 6 1/4" x 8"; Pepper, George Wharton, 1867-1961
    Washington, T.L.S. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 16, undated; 8" x 10"; Sacken, C.
    [Philadelphia], ----. 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Thanks Mr. Vaughan for permission to visit the Athenaeum. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 22, undated; 7 7/8" x 9 13/16"; Storer, J. P. B.
    Cambridge, ----. 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. J. B. S. Rangel, of Pernambuco, Brazil. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 25, undated; 10x8; Hopkinson, Joseph, 1770-1842
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Declines invitation to breakfast. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 5, undated; 7 7/8" x 9 11/16"; Coffin, William
    New York, ----. 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Thanks Mr. Vaughan for his "very friendly attentions" before leaving for England. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to E.W. Clark, June 16, undated; 4 1/2" x 8"; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for subscription. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, July 12, undated; 4 7/8" x 7 1/2"; Preston, William C.
    Mansion House, [Philadelphia], ----. 1 p. A.L.S. Thanks Mr. Vaughan for his kindness. "We of the South are always your debtors." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 6, undated; 7 7/8" x 12 3/4"; Collins, Zaccheus, 1764-1831
    [Philadelphia], ----. 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Regarding a certain species of cicada and its ravages on the vine. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Snider, August 26, undated; 4" x 5 1/4"; Hahnemann
    [Paris] []. A.L. in 3d P. 1p. also envelope and calling card. In French. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, September 23, undated; 5" x 7 3/4"; Bradford, T. G. (Thomas Gamaliel), 1802-1887
    1 p. and address. A.L.S. Thanks Mr. Vaughan for his "constant and unwearied kindness" during his stay in Philadelphia. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, undated; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Bowditch, Henry I. (Henry Ingersoll), 1808-1892
    [Philadelphia], Friday evening, n. d. 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Regrets that he will be unable to breakfast with Mr. Vaughan, as he leaves town at 7 a. m. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, undated; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842
    ----, n. d. 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Encloses letter for Judge Hopkinson. Has told him that Mr. Vaughan will send him "my two volumes." Will be in Philadelphia today---hopes to see Mr. Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, undated; 8" x 9 7/8"; Dahlgren, John A.
    n. d. 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Concerning "a slight discrepancy in the value assigned the old French foot." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [ ] Madeira, undated; 6 1/4" x 8"; Davis, Richard Harding, 1864-1916
    n.d. A.L.S. 2p. Congratulations re. marriage of Ms. Clark. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Extracts from letters of John Dickinson to Geo. Logan, undated; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Dickinson, John, 1732-1808
    copied in a ms. biographical account of the latter drawn up by Mrs. Deborah Logan...and intended to be deposited by her in the Loganian library, p. 105 of ms. Ext. by Jn. Vaughan, D. 3p. and end. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, undated; 7 3/4" x 9 11/16"; Dwight, Henry E.
    Philadelphia, Thursday morning, n.d. 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Encloses prospectus of course of lectures he delivered in New York. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, undated; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Gray, Thomas
    Roxbury, n. d. 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Concerning the Unitarian Society. Hopes that Mr. Vaughan will find a young man to succeed him in his church. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, undated; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Lee, Richard Henry, 1794-1865
    Tuesday evening, 10 o'clock. A.L.S. 1p. and add. Thanks Vaughan for his visit and for book. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, undated; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Lieber, Francis, 1800-1872
    [Philadelphia], Thursday morning, n. d. 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Regrets that he did not meet the Austrian minister. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Introducing Mr. John Vaughan., undated; 8-1/2x11; Madeira, Edward W.
    Typed D. [36 leaves] Quotes many letters from the Franklin Papers in the APS. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, undated; 7 13/16" x 10"; O'Brien, M.
    ----, n. d. 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Wishes to borrow $100 from Mr. Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, undated; 8" x 9 7/8"; Sargent, John T.
    n. d. 1p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Francis Dwight of Springfield. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, undated; 4 7/8" x 8 1/4"; Taylor, James.
    ----, n.d.3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Criticism of an article upon Hebrew grammar in the Gentleman's Magazine. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Biographical note about the Vaughan family, undated; 10" x 15 1/2"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 2p. Biographical sketch covering the period to 1782. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - List of names with amounts of money paid., undated; 7-3/4x6 1/4; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 1p. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - List of names with amount of contributions or dues [for the Unitarians ?]., undated; 10x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 6p. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, undated; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Walsh, Robert
    Brandywine Springs, Friday morning, n. d. 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Regarding an article upon negro slavery. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, undated; 7 1/4" x 9"; Ware, W.
    ----, n. d. 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Jenkes, of Providence, Rhode Island. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, undated; Anonymous
    Photostat. 1 p. Concerning the money due to Mr. Punstall. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Remedy against “la Goutte”, undated; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Attributed to John Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Poetry addressed to E. W. Clark, undated; Pop, Hannah
    Love poem. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Verses to Hannah Pop (?), undated
  - Autograph, undated; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863
  - Miscellaneous notes by E.W. Madeira, undated; Includes a bound essay and a scrapbook.; Madeira, Edward W.
    This box includes a scrapbook with research notes and copies of Vaughan letters gathered by Edward W. Madeira during his research on John Vaughan (1776-1783). Also included is Madeira's essay "Introducing Mr. John Vaughan," which consists mainly of Vaughan correspondence (1776-1782).
- Series II: Volumes, 3.0 Volume(s); Three volumes.; This series includes two commonplace books (1779; c. 1783), and one copybook with letters, dated 1784 to 1801.
  - Commonplace book, 1779; 870 L34; 1.0 Volume(s); "Latin quotations." Includes quotations in Latin, and an alphabetically-arranged list of books, probably either those purchased, read, or owned.; 1 volume, 47 pp.; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841 (Volume 1)
    870 L34.
    The book, inscribed "J Vaughan his book May 17, 1779," includes Latin notations on terms such as Virtue, Avaritia, Satisfactio, Prosperitas, Invidia, and Juventus. Beginning on p. 29 is an alphabetical list of books, with marks that may indicate whether Vaughan read or owned them. One notation near the end of the volume indicates that John Frazer borrowed Bartram's Travels in August 1792.
    Commonplace books.
  - Commonplace book, c. 1783; A.D. 92p. of which 26 are blank.
    This volume was located among old papers of the society.
    This volume, which was written shortly after Vaughan's arrival in Philadelphia, offers a variety of information on a wide range of topics. There are, for example, remarks on many prominent Americans, such as Rush, Rittenhouse, Priestley, Franklin, Washington and Jefferson, among others. The entry on Rush, for example, list Rush's observation "whilst in the American army," a section titled "Orrery" discusses Rittenhouse's telescope, a a few remarks on General Greene's "Military genius." There are short notes and extended essays on topics such as the American Philosophical Society, population numbers, the "Hygrometer," Congress, the state constitutions, and Sweden.
    The volume also contains much information pertaining to the U.S. for use by a merchant, such as "commission of selling goods in Philadelphia," sailboats from New York to Florida, and "Wheat-Expence of a cargo at London." There are also numerous entries concerning American culture, society and economy. States that are discussed in particular detail include Virginia, Maryland, Georgia, New York, and especially Pennsylvania.
    Of interest is also an essay titled "Observations repecting the Indians," which focuses on diet and diseases among Native Americans. A shorter entry deals with "Indian hostilities" and their causes.
    At the end of the volume are notes about the government of Denmark and the "Dominions of Britain." There is also an extract of a letter from Benjamin Rush, dated 1782, accompanied by a newspaper clipping from 1783, and an extract from a letter by Alexander Hamilton regarding the death of Major Andre, dated 1780.
    B V462.c. FILM 54-67 FRAME 6
  - Copybook, 1782-1801; D. [1] 22 [i.e.21] leaves in bound volume.
    The letters, which are not entered into the copybook in chronological order, were written by John Vaughan between 1782 and 1801. The recipients include a number of prominent Americans, such as John Jay, Joseph Priestley, Robert Fulton, and Henry Laurens. There are also several letters to family members, including Samuel, William, and Benjamin Vaughan. The correspondece deals with political, scientific, commercial, and personal matters.
    Many of the letters shed light on Vaughan’s efforts to resolve a disagreement between John Jay and Brockholst Livingston. The two men evidently differed in their accounts of what happened to a number of dispatches from Jay to the Continental Congress when Vaughan and Livingston were captured by an English frigate in 1782. Jay had entrusted to Vaughan several “Public Dispatches” (March 18, 1786). A letter to Livingston confirms that Vaughan was instructed to throw the packet of dispatches “overboard in case of danger” (June 27, 1786). The copybook includes copies of two letters from Vaughan to Jay that were destroyed when Vaughan was captured (Feb. 26, 1782; March 5, 1782).
    Several letters, including the one to Samuel Vaughan (May 22, 1790), deal with commercial matters, such as trade regulations. The letters to Benjamin Vaughan deal with a range of topics, including politics, scientific matters, and personal affairs. Several letters, for example, discuss challenges to the priority of invention of Mr. Ramsay’s “application of Steams to Navigations” (May 15, 24, June 4, 1788). The letter of June 4, 1788, also includes comments on the new government in Carolina, notes on Joseph Priestley, and observations on Charles Willson Peale’s preparations to exhibit the mammoth. Vaughan, who supported Priestley’s immigration to the United States, claimed not to “be surprised if immigrations are consequent upon the Countenance given in England to illiberal + intolerant Sentiments religious + political” (Oct. 3, 1791). His letters to Priestley are filled with sympathy for the “illiberal + unmanly Sentiments” expressed toward Priestley in England (October 3, 1791).
    Of interest is also a letter to Robert Fulton, possibly erroneously dated July 23, 1801, six years before Fulton's first successful run of a steamboat, in which Vaughan comments on an engraving of a steamboat. Finally, two items reflect Vaughan’s efforts to improve his writing habits. In a letter to Samuel Vaughan, he thanks him “for the hint about my letters which I shall improve upon” (Nov. 20, 1784), and on a different occasion, he offers his gratitude to Henry Laurens for “the kindness in correcting an impropriety which had degenerated into habit” (May 10, 1786).
    B V462.1.
    - Letter to John Jay, Madrid, Feb. 26, 1782; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      Cadiz, L.S.with initials. 3p. Copy. (see J. Vaughan. Copies of...letters, pp.4-6.) Sails for the U.S. shortly and will deliver, or sink, the dispatches for the Continental congress.
    - Letter to J[ohn] Jay, Madrid, March 5, 1782; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      Cadiz, L.S.with initials. 2p. Copy. (see J. Vaughan. Copies of...letters, pp.6-7.) Will said shortly. Concerning special dispatches.
    - Letter to Sam[ue]l Vaughan & son, London, Nov. 20, 1784; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      Philadelphia, L.S.with initials. 1p. Copy. (see J.Vaughan. Copies of...letters, p.1.) Will try to write more fully.
    - Letter to Henry Lawrens [sic], Charleston, Dec. 10, 1785; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      L.S.with initials. 1p. Copy. (see J.Vaughan. Copies of...letters, p.1.) Hopes his life will be pleasant and still of public service.
    - Letter to [Henry] Brockholst Livingston, New York, Jan. 3, 1786; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      L.S.with initials. 2p. Copy. (see J.Vaughan. Copies of...letters, pp.1-2.) Hopes that he and John Jay become friends again.
    - Letter to John Jay,New York, Feb. 2, 1786; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      L.S.with initials. 2p. Copy. (see J.Vaughan. Copies of...letters,pp.2-3.) Concerning his and B.Livingston's trip from Spain to the U. S.
    - Letter to [Henry] Brockholst Livingston, New York, March 18, 1786; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1757-1839
      L.S.with initials. 1p. Copy. (see J. Vaughan. Copies of...letters, p.3.) Affirms that they destroyed Jay's dispatches when the British captured them in 1782.
    - Letter to Henry Laurens, May 10, 1786; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      Philadelphia, L.S.with initials. 1p. Copy. (see J.Vaughan. Copies of...letters, p.4.) Will be more careful, hereafter, in signing his name.
    - Letter to [Henry] Brockholst Livingston, New York, June 27, 1786; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      L.S.with initials. 2p. Copy. (see J. Vaughan. Copies of...letters, pp.7-8.) Concerning the trouble between Livingston and Jay.
    - Letter to John Jay, New York, June 28, 1786; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      Philadelphia, L.S.with initials. 1p. Copy. (see J. Vaughan. Copies of...letters, p.8.) Encloses copy of letter he wrote H.B. Livingston.
    - Letter to [Henry] Brockholst Livingston, New York, July 12, 1786; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      Philadelphia, L.S.with initials. 2p. Copy. (see J.Vaughan. Copies of...letters, pp.8-9.) Concerning the difficulty with Jay.
    - Letter to John Jay, New York, Aug. 11, 1786; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      L.S.with initials. 2p. Copy. (see J. Vaughan. Copies of...letters, pp.9-10.) Introduces Henry A. Dohrman, who aided Americans in Lisbon during the Revolution. He, now, needs aid.
    - Letter to Henry Laurence [Laurens], Charleston, Oct. 17, 1786; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      Philadelphia, L.S.with initials. 1p. Copy. (see J. Vaughan. Copies of...letters, p.10.) Current events.
    - Letter to Henry Lawrence [Laurens], Charleston, Aug. 11, 1787; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      L.S.with initials. 2p. Copy. (see J.Vaughan. Copies of...letters, pp.10-11) Business matters, which will have to wait until Samuel Vaughan returns. Refers to the constitutional convention.
    - Letter to Benj[amin] Vaughan, May 15, 1788; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      Philadelphia, L.S.with initials. 2p. Copy. (see J.Vaughan. Copies of...letters,pp.11-12.) Concerning Rumsey and his invention of the steam boat. He bears a letter to B.Vaughan from "Dr Frankling". FILM 54-65 FRAME 192
    - Letter to Benj[amin] Vaughan, London, May 24, 1788; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      Philadelphia, L.S.with initials. 2p. Copy. (see J.Vaughan. Copies of...letters, p.12.) Concerning Ramsay [Rumsey] and Fitch and their fight over priority of invention of boilers for steam navigation.
    - Letter to Benj[amin] Vaughan, London, June 4, 1788; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      Philadelphia, L.S.with initials. 2p. Copy. (see J. Vaughan. Copies of...letters, pp.12-13.) Concerning U.S. politics. Concerning Priestley and his publications. Refers to Franklin and Jay. FILM54-65 FRAME191
    - Letter to Benj[amin] Vaughan, London, Nov. 3, 1788; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      Philadelphia, L.S.with initials. 2p. Copy. (see J.Vaughan. Copies of...letters, p.13-14.) Introduces Mr. Bush who has discovered a cure for cancer.
    - Letter to J[ean] H[yacinthe de] Magellan, London, Feb.19, 1789; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
      Philadelphia, L.S.with initials. 1p. Copy. (see J. Vaughan. Copies of...letters, p.16.) Concerning the actual value of U.S. money.